Sufyan Saleem

Address: Phase 6, Sector F8, Street 4, House 425, Hayatabad, Peshawar **Email**: sufyansalim94@gmail.com

Mobile: +923139243550

OBJECTIVE

I am a 24 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Islamabad Linknbit Pakistan Jan 2019 - present Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include developing Websites, Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications. Global Aviation System I am working on parts of Jan 2019 – present backend Node JS, Express, For Central African Republic Swagger, Sequelize cli & Azure In Development SQL **Dynasty Unleashed Models** Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Modeling agency App for Fashion Deployment to Firebase & designers and marketers Google Play Users can register, create profile, add people and hire models at will Dokkani.co React/React-Native, Expo. Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Ecommerce Mobile App. Woo Commerce API. User can register, select products, Native Base add products to cart. User add products to wish list and checkout. Website Project was abandoned on last stage before deployment due to funds not provided. Yogurt App Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Step-by-step guide to home crafted **Native Base** authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate. **SmartsAid** React/React-Native, Expo,

NGO App for refuges

Redux, Firebase, Rest API,

React Native Elements

2018 - FYP Currency Recognition & Conversion Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and also show the exchange rate in USD. 2014 - 2018 Content Management Systems Java, C#, MSSQL Gym - Point of Sale PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL 2010 RuneScape RPG Java Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game DevCamper API HTML, NodeJS, Express,

Portfolio Projects

Bootcamps API

One can register as a User or Publisher and login also.

Publisher can create Bootcamps.

Admin and Publisher can add courses and perform various CRUD operations.

Users can comment on Bootcamps and update their profile, add picture, and reset password.

DevConnector

Social Media for developers where users register.

Create profile, create posts, add comments and like and unlike them. React, Redux, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, NodeJS, Heroku

Mongoose,

Injection

MongoDB, Node mailer,

Security for XSS and NOSQL

SmartBrain

Smart Brain an app with face Recognition.

Users can register, login and submit images via URL.

The AI recognizes the face in the picture and draw a border around.

It works only for one face in the image.

React, Redux, CSS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Express, Nodejs, Heroku, Netlify

EDUCATION

Internet of things and AI Specialist Course

PIAIC, Islamabad (2019 - present)

BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE

Specialities

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

Social Links









Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB HTML, CSS, Bootstrap Git, Heroku Rust Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES

Languages

English Urdu Pashto

Hobbies

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding,